astro-charts.com 2008-06-11

# Essential Astrology - Privacy Statement

**Use of Cookies**  
Essential Astrology uses "cookies" to help you personalise your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Essential Astrology services or web sites you visit. 

**IP Addresses**  
Essential Astrology uses IP addresses (random numbers assigned to individual computers) to help diagnose problems with our servers, administer our Web site and anonymously track content preferences and traffic patterns. 

**Security of your Personal Information**  
Essential Astrology is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorised access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access that are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it with encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

**Usage tracking**  
Essential Astrology tracks user traffic patterns throughout the sites in the Essential Astrology portfolio and this information is correlated with data about individual users. Overall usage statistics, according to a user's domain name, browser type and MIME type retrieved by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser), are also broken down. 

Essential Astrology also tracks and catalogues the search terms that customers enter into our search tools, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. Essential Astrology uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalised elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. 

We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. Essential Astrology does not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in our search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. However, we do not track which terms a particular user enters. 

**What information do we collect?**  
The types of information collected might include names, date of birth, e-mail address, postal address, telephone number, fax number and credit/debit card details. 

**How do we use this information?**  
We will use your personal information to provide you with the services, products or information you have requested and for administration purposes. We may need to share your information with our service providers, associated organisations and agents for these purposes, for example, if we arrange for you to view a property advertised on one of our websites. 

**Users 16 and under**  
Essential Astrology is committed to protecting the safety and privacy of young people using the Internet. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information about children. If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide personal information to any websites in theEssential Astrology portfolio. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information. 

**Use of Privacy Statements byEssential Astrology Partners and Affiliates**  
While Essential Astrology supports other web site operators complying with these principles, you should carefully examine the privacy statements of sites linking to or from Essential Astrology. Personal information that you choose to provide to other web sites will be subject to the privacy policies of that specific web site. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. 

**Access to your personal information**  
You have the right to request a copy of the personal information Essential Astrology holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. (We charge ?5 for information requests.) Please address requests to Essential Astrology, 

**Changes to this Statement**  
Essential Astrology will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect company and customer feedback. When Essential Astrology posts changes to this Statement, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the Privacy Statement. If there are material changes to this Statement, Essential Astrology will notify you by placing prominent notice on the Web site. Essential Astrology encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how we are protecting your information. 

**Contact Information**  
If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Statement, please contact me.
